# Louise Pike

# Software Engineer

https://louise-pike.netlify.app/
https://github.com/stars/louisep1/lists/portfolio

louisepike@live.co.uk https://www.linkedin.com/in/louise-pike-82b2b9247/

# **Work Experience**

#### Software Engineer | Pyxos Corp

Japan

December 2022 to December 2023 (1 year)

**Project:** Software as a service (SaaS), cloud-based patient management software application (developed in-house and sold as a subscription service to clients)

Clients: Veterinary clinics across Japan (users: hospital staff & pet owners)

**Objectives:** To develop new features for the app and optimize usability

**Outcome:** Increase in new clients due to greater app functionality through addition of in-demand features, and higher customer satisfaction of existing clients, boosting client retention by addressing their needs.

**Product Details:** Calendar (in real-time) for appointments, digital patient record (medical and financial data entries for each appointment, including freeflow text input, ability to upload images, documenting prescriptions and dosage amounts, breakdown of billing charges calculated according to discounts or insurance coverage, history of saved changes), payment records.

#### **Specific Role Highlights:**

- Collaborated in team of 4 Japanese engineers, adhering to kanban style agile development principles.
- Oversaw the entire development process: planning, UI and API structure design, decision-making for necessary changes, implementation of ideas, creation and testing phases.
- Built REST APIs to store and retrieve user data, ensuring correct user authentication and authorization access rights.
- Built reactive, dynamic UI to respond to front-end state management changes, both from incoming response data from the server and from user inputted changes in the browser.
- Proactively responded to client requests and fixed bugs.
- Wrote rigorous unit tests to ensure each change was compatible and prevent breakage in the code.
- Conducted code reviews, to improve code quality, readibility and uniformity.
- Atomic design for frontend file structure for ease of reusability of components.

#### Implemented Feature Example:

Incorporation of Insurance Company A. The aim was for pet owners who use said insurance company to claim insurance coverage electronically and directly upon being billed at the clinic, so that they could pay only what they owe. Removed the need for additional paperwork, both from the clinic and pet owners, as the new feature would communicate with the external API of the insurance company, specifically, to retrieve comfirmation that pet owners are authorised to use this insurance within the application and to send records of actual insurance usage back to the insurance company. Wrote complex logic to check for eligibility then ensure accurate and reliable calculations of hospital costs in different scenarios. Created new API endpoints and database tables to accompany the new data sets.

**Technologies:** JavaScript, Vue.js, Vuex, Node.js, Express, SQL, Sequelize, Jest, Vue Test Utils, Sass/SCSS, HTML, Jest, Google Cloud Platform, Git, TypeScript, Socket.io

# **Summary**

Highly-motivated software engineer, specialising in full stack web development. As a developer, I enjoy the challenge of continually learning and solving problems and find great fulfillment in seeing code work successfully and in building new and innovative features.

# **Tech stack / Skills**

#### Frontend:

JavaScript TypeScript CSS HTML Vue.js Vuex React React Router Redux Redux Toolkit Jest Sass/SCSS Bootstrap Tailwind CSS Daisy UI Axios

#### Backend:

Node.js Express MySQL SQL Sequelize NoSQL MongoDB Mongoose JSON Web Token Bcrypt

#### **Additional tools/skills:**

GitHub/GitHub Desktop Postman HeidiSQL MySQL Workbench XAMPP phpMyAdmin MongoDB Compass Firebase/Firestore PayPal Sandbox Heroku Render Agile development Kanban

# **Portfolio Projects**

#### Clean Hotels | React, MySQL, Sass (Prior to December 2022)

Using React and Sass/SCSS in the frontend and MySQL, Express and Node.js in the backend, users can browse the page of this small chain of local hotels and reserve a room today. https://clean-hotels.onrender.com

#### Event Ticket Page | Node.js, Mongoose, Bootstrap (Prior to December 2022)

Using React with Bootstrap styling in the frontend and MongoDB, Mongoose and Express in the backend, this full stack app allows users to buy and sell tickets to their favourite events.

https://event-ticket-page.onrender.com/

#### Social Networking App | DaisyUI, Tailwind, React (Prior to December 2022)

The Social Network App is a mobile-first messaging page, built with React, Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI in the frontend, inspired by popular modern-day messaging services and designed for optimum use on a mobile device. Users can search for friends by email address and send messages.

https://social-network-app.onrender.com/

# **Past Work Experience**

#### **Educator | Yaruki Switch Group**

Japan

July 2019 to July 2022 (3 years)

- Teaching children with very little English experience and exposure.
- Focus on active language production.
- Adept at working with clients (students) directly, face-to-face, considering their needs, goals and requirements.
- Worked within a diverse team of Japanese and international staff.

#### **Nursery Manager | Tinysaurus Nurseries**



February 2018 to March 2019 (1 year)

- Started as a Trainee Manager, then Assistant Manager, then Nursery Manager
- Leadership of staff and overseeing tasks, officer of health and safety, delivering training, recruitment, marketing, ensuring customer satisfaction, dealing with complains and issues.

#### **Receptionist | Kicks Martial Arts Center**

January 2016 to July 2019 (3½ years)

- Part-time work as a receptionist at a local martial arts centre.
- Teamwork and communication were essential to this smaller, family-run business.

#### **Activities Coordinator | Lyndhurst Rest Homes**

August 2016 to March 2017 (1/2 year)

• Organised activities for elderly residents in a care home. (Part-time)

## **Education History**



CELTA (Cambridge English Level 5 Certificate in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages) | St Giles, Brighton

*April – May 2019* Grade A Pass



MA International Education and Development | University of Sussex

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017

Merit

BA Childhood and Youth | University of Sussex

Sept 2013 - July 2016 First Class Honours

## Languages

EnglishJapaneseSpanishNativeConversationalBasic

# **Passions**

Dance Scuba diving Travel Outdoors Walking Learning Languages